Guide to the Yale Women's Action Committee Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Women's Action Committee records
1975-1985
RU 477
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
(1 box)
The records consist of clippings, reports, and correspondence documenting the Yale Women's Action Committee study of sexual and gender harassment at Yale. Also includes a report and newsclipping concerning sexual harassment at Harvard.
Yale Women's Action Committee
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Yale Women's Action Committee, 1993.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of clippings, reports, and correspondence documenting the Yale Women's Action Committee study of sexual and gender harassment at Yale. Also includes a report and newsclipping concerning sexual harassment at Harvard.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Sex discrimination against women; Sexual harassment in universities and colleges; Women college teachers; Women in education; Yale University -- Appointments, promotions, salaries, etc.; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale Women's Action Committee
- Sexual and gender harassment files, 1975-1985; Accession 1994-A-003
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2021.
  - Harvard: Sexual Harassment- Newspaper Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Harvard: Report on a Sexual Harassment Survey, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yale School of Medicine Report on Faculty Salaries, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Sexual and Gender Harassment in the Academy" - Franklin, Moglen, Angress, Zatlin-Boring, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yale Grievance Board and Opinions Of It, 1980, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sexual Harassment- Correspondence, Reports, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
  - Sexual Harassment- Non-Newspaper, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sexual Harassment- Newspaper Clippings, 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yale Women's Action Committee- Selected Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Yale Fair Practices Survey, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Yale Fair Practices Survey- Completed, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Redacted files
    Restricted until January 1, 2061
    - Riley-References, Correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Riley-EEOC, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Riley v. Yale University- Small Claims, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)